# **AARON VONTELL**

860-805-0050 vontell@mit.edu github.com/vontell

229 Vassar Street Cambridge, MA 02139

#### **Profile**

I am a freshman at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, pursuing a degree in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. I have three years of computer programming experience, mainly in Java and Android. I also completed a summer internship at Cigna on an Android Application Developer team.

### **Experience**

Android Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2014 Duties included developing proof-of-concept software and Android applications using the Java programming language, in conjunction with external libraries and devices. Multiple projects were completed in accordance to a schedule, and collaboration and teamwork were used throughout each project.

Lead Software Developer, Parcio; Boston, MA — 2014 - Present

Duties included developing an Android and iOS application with the startup Parcio.

The application included work with Google APIs, MapQuest Open APIs, Android SDK, and iOS development. Also required multiple meetings with city officials and the department of transportation. See more at parcio.com

Admissions Employee, Lake Compounce; Bristol, Connecticut — 2013-2014 Duties at this amusement park included working a register efficiently, conversing with guests to help them with any issues, and working as a team to sustain the park's image. My main assignments were working the cash registers and working in Guest Relations to help guests with anything from lost tickets to lost children.

#### Education

Attended University High School of Science and Engineering, 2010 - 2014

40+ college credits from University of Hartford during high school, 2011 - 2014

Currently enrolled in Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2014 - present

Pursuing Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Major, Minor in Management

## **Skills**

Java Programming (3+ years)

Android Programming (Including multiple APIs) (1 year)

Project Management (From a leadership role on a FIRST Robotics team for 6 years)

Photoshop CS6

Minimal Experience in HTML, CSS, Objective-C, and Python

Autodesk Inventor Professional